that's what Musti
well maybe I'll start at a questioning
I'll see where it takes us mm-hmm what is
how would you describe in its content a
thought
the images of [Applause]
[Applause]
or things that I've seen in that I have
perceived and images of perception okay
so what is the and perceptions how did
them no perceptions what is a perception
its content
geez he's come ya know or what you see
things that are seen the particular
types of sight so let's look at
something tape measure so you're looking
at a tape measure what is in its content
of your site with shape color shape the
color what is a shape color any content
what is a shape the designation shape
shape color color what is that in your
mind of an image I suppose it's thing
closer so it's a yeah that's fine you
can call an image so it's an image so
then is your perception and image as in
an actual perception is this also an
image in your mind
yeah it's a different type of as
mother's was the difference what we did
to her was like if I'm thinking behind
imagining hey mister okay okay
and then when I've seen one yeah it's a
different quality but what is in common
what is in common to the site of the
temperature and now to you thought of it
what is in common the flute
the flute
sure but what is the content on the
floor then like cuz yeah I'm hearing
about abstract thought and I sure
thought theoretical clear ambiguous
order why do they all have in common
what do all thoughts have in common a
thoughts but in terms of the content why
do they all have in common what is the
common characteristic of all the
thoughts what do they all have you said
it well the images they have in an image
literally anyway so the thoughts and an
image is different well I'm trying to
clarify here in a sense that image is
it's like with a specific it's within a
thought so you can have you can't have
thoughts without images but images are
more precise thoughts so to speak so you
can call them thoughts Thomas you can
call it phenomena images of content but
that's the thing you don't start with a
pure recognition of image as a content
you start with heavy concepts of
abstract thoughts ideas designations so
you need to make the effort through
those ideas and designations to discern
a certain enduring container of an image
which is what gives the identity through
thought as a thought so that's I mean
thought is a more broader application of
the term but more specifically images so
can you say so something has manifested
yeah doesn't the characteristic of
images and exactly also gonna science at
that I can only know that because this
one image yeah exactly exactly so what
I'm saying
in the same sense in the previous talk
we spoke about the resisting aspect of
your thought that's what images are
because you have no say in having
appeared to you in how it manifested yet
that is an image of home
you can think further and further and
further so yeah you said correctly in a
way there is a difference between you
imagining your images and you perceiving
but there is also the common ground to
it and that common ground is not an
external relationship their common
ground is a necessary container for both
you wouldn't be able to think this
particular tape measurer if you've never
seen it and you've never seen it if you
never had an image in your mind of it
that's why you can sometimes not see it
but I can describe it to you and then
you can see it and recognize it as the
same thing because it's the same basis
or the same images and any difference in
like my description in what you saw
like if the difference is not sufficient
for you to doubt the identity of the
thing you realize oh no that's the thing
you're talking about nah I understand it
correctly now so perceptions and
imagination are mental images so whether
you perceive whether you imagine images
are there so in other words perception
is basically images of the senses and
imagination is images upon the images
but you're inside a image
represents what no sense absolutely not
because that assumes there is that you
can even conceive rightly that from
which my perception came about and how
can you know that unless you're
perceiving it which means how can you
perceive what comes before perception so
this is before my perception that's an
assumption it's reticence that's an assumption of
it's reticence that's an assumption of
the external world that's the deaths
that's how you allow the footing for the
matter because it's because of the
matter that you perceive but see when
thinking eyes that's the real matter
know that you can only perceive it which
means you can only perceive your
perception and then you get to assume
that matter behind ya
will you say a feeling is an image
imaged Evan yeah everything the manifest is an
Evan yeah everything the manifest is an
image on the level of manifestation yeah
and that's why I said I wanted to use
the word image not the word thought
because then people on us only when I
think it it's real no you can only think
something if the images are there and
you don't have to think it you can just
look at it and that's the common ground
they probably many people would struggle
to find between senses or as ended the
physical and the mental because it's
usually the senses and now I mean my
thoughts as a result of it know where
the sense is whether my thoughts images
are their perceptual images are there
that's why it's on the level of
perception images as well say somebody
somebody not mindful that they're kind
of not really thinking about what
they're doing but they're doing some
things aiming at towards something so
that thing that they're aiming at
they're not actually aware of what it is
they're aiming at mmm it's still present
as an image yeah yeah it's just not
something that they're actually going
look that's the thing that I'm and
you're assailed the same thing I don't
know what I want the dead steam usually
I'm having in mind yeah you have a vague
in the biggest direction I don't know
what I want but clearly you're doing
something about it in some way which
means you have some sense so what it a
sense a thought
I'm biggest idea abstract theory actual
perception of sight sound smell taste
touch images are there because literally
Dhamma could be translated as an image
phenomena an image thank you I think
so would you say the image is also like
what's designated the designation of
whatever whatever it is this manifested
so some things there is designated in
some way that's the image that's all in
the beginning of your designation sure
yeah yeah yeah
can you have an image without the color
of it okay so that's why the good of
this kind of perception it's fundamental
terms he perceives yellow white blue red
that's it but you can have a an image
without so sure you can but you can't
have an image without the color no
without space without space exactly
that's where you can use space
practically to surmount the sense of it
you can have an image without a touch
suppose well it's it's like there's not
much you can designate not much
difference or designee between the touch
your first point of touch is the first
point in resistance which is this body
as a whole so the image wouldn't stand
for that but is not what you can
describe about them but if you want to
describe the characteristic of an image
yeah it has to be color has to be shape
which means has to have space has to be
in off space has to be same so so so if
I have an image so if I have an image of
a taste I have the image of the taste
yeah the experience of a think it's
there's something salty yeah can you
imagine salty deafness without color
yeah you can can you imagine color with
us alternates you can because I because
the senses also they're not linear the
whole arrangement within material
arrangement of his sense organs is such
he has its own arrangement they're not
all on the same field so to speak on the
same level ground so but can you also
can you even can you imagine saltiness
without tasting it and kicking up you
have the idea of saltiness but it's
already quite secondary but you can't
imagine blue and it will go all the way
to the point of the image whatever you
can imagine yellow literally you have
image of yellow in your mind but
saltiness without taste that you're not
tasting your mouth you can be hoping to
taste it but it's gonna be more on a
level of secondary concept because
you'll be really when you imagine
saltiness you're imagining yourself eating some
you're imagining yourself eating some
salty food which is more like images of
colors and shapes are you consuming so
they then get to taste like this unisys
all to see quite sure yes that the
perception of salt is experienced
through the eye well that's why the kind
of an obsession is are in the perception
of the image of tastes this image of the
image of tastes so no the perceptual tag
isn't worried yes yeah not specifically
through the eye but you could say
through the mental eye that's to be an
image yeah yeah even if you were like
blind your whole life you will have to
have an image of your experience as a
whole of consuming some object in your
mouth they was producing the salty taste for
they was producing the salty taste for
you but you can't imagine the pure salt
in this in itself but that's beside the
point now are these particular senses
which comes first doesn't matter
whichever way they come an image has to
be there
many people confuse why would you be
describing the perception in terms of
colors these images it's because yeah
that's what it will boil down to and you
can't describe it also in terms of space
that's where space is sometimes listed
as one of the elements it's not
fundamental elements like format
abilities but it's out there with
consciousness and another maja would
select the six elements
so you said why
everything every image has a color if
you first every image is because now
when you think every much has a color
yeah same color it's another image for
you so what you're really saying is
every image has an image and that's true
but that's not practically accurate so
there is an image within which you
discern the properties of color
characteristics of it's being manifested
so think space when I say space what
image is present in your mind space
space what's present in your mind
something clear something clear but I
say space what's present mind is the
word space literally written word space
it was presently much but yeah whatever
I was getting expansive so the point is
there has to be a limit of some and
there has to be if I say I don't know I
tell them in another language that you
don't understand yeah you still have to
have an image in your mind of based on
the basis of sounds and I just produced
that you you will have an image of what
what does that mean no this is this
gibberish or this particular language or
you will have to have some image always
there is no such thing as an image less
mind unless neither perception or
perception and so on okay even space
bases of infinite space is based of
infinite image yeah image of
infiniteness of space but both never lay
even if you're not that's something's
gone as an image within that image you
will discern various perceptions well we
did that image will discern the five
senses that's what we did that image you
desire you discern more images yeah
within their image you discern your
intentions yeah so it's it's Airy this I
can affirm
a sort of starting image which is
basically the image of this experience
yeah and the starting image does not
disappear when the second thing comes in
now starting image remains is a primary
soul only container baby which yeah yeah
you can't be outside of it but that's
where the mind comes first David comes
first so the primary image you thinking
outside of oh there's outside of this
image attending yours is another image
Juiz these experiences sorry the
experience as a whole
yeah of course that's what they
experience as a whole when I say imagine
your experience as a whole or don't
imagine your experience at all come back
to the body be here now present the
present moment what is what is present
with you in the most acute sense you're
not specifically looking looking what I
might be doing if I'm doing some sort of
meditation technique but if I'm not
falling into that trap and so you just
want to be present what is the closest
thing to to you it's an image of the
Mystics beta so that's the point you
can't really have anything other than
that even if you want to but the problem
is when you have images yet here you are
thinking you're observing the actual
form and you think you're observing the
matter the reality behind you think
you're observing physical sensations and
whatnot all you're observing is images
enduring on a counter which you end up
misconceiving those images as matter
misconceiving those images as feelings
as perceptions as intentions as
basically misconceiving the aggregates
or rather conceiving decades given them
the being assuming them appropriately
now think about me myself
can you even think that without an image
certain degree a certain independence of
a aspect of that thought I am there's a
certain shape to it but usually gets
associated with your own face instructor
veiled in the background but the point
is and image is there doesn't matter how
ambiguous how subtle image has to be
there and not being trained in regard to
those images means not being training
they got your mind and that's how you've
always then be governed by their kind of
these assumed directions that there's
images take you even if my face means me
I am my control master owner
appropriator oh that's implied not seeing it you took
oh that's implied not seeing it you took
it upon yourself so leave you mind blank
what is that you can what is that
it's another image yeah so yeah it's not
truly blank because well but how can you
even designate blankness unless it's
absence of something else which is then
an image present in your mind in regards
to this which is absence of that image
think about in Peru yeah well yeah so
see that's the whole the the design of
emptiness that the Buddha was talking
about like imagine when you go into the
empty Hut and even as this place is
empty of other people so it's actually
factually perceiving an image of absence
of others fully develop that image and
then apply to yourself oh so so is this
experience as a whole in its entirety
this image is absent of persons that's
it because you clarified this the the
the sign of emptiness the
characteristics of emptiness means you
see there's a clear image
now you see the also pertaining to your
own experience as a whole it's not empty
empty just space out and rule sort of us
out unconscious no it's empty of this
this experience is empty of lust it's
empty of a version it's empty of
delusion so if I say emptiness but
present in mine
emptiness
what image is there nothingness okay so
what are the character is what some
people nothingness empties but what is
the curse of empty space so then the
space is there so there is a certain
container but it's empty so things that
things could be in that yeah but the
point is so things that are making the
space empty are there as absence as a
negative presence because if there is
nothing that could be in there you
wouldn't say this is empty of so now
we'll just me this is so so the
nothingness of what then
nothingness when I ask you emptiness
when you say oh it's nothing
nothingness I said well what is the
character is from nothingness okay Clara
stick is empty space empty of what that
space until what what is the absence in
that space in that nothingness that
comes to your mind when I keep repeating
nothingness nothingness nothingness
nothingness absence of something absence
of something well but that's all it is
something isn't it
nothingness what I said is something so
you can say it's absence of something
because then it's not absence of itself
yeah so more specifically nothingness or
emptiness more accurately empty of what
and give everything else this what are
the characteristics of being empty don't
necessarily look for the attentive this
to dismiss characteristics of being
empty as we just described it he has to
become negative it's the exactly
negative presence were born in presence
or the absence so the value on the
presence of absence already empty no
it's not really empty as in it's no
really empty new assumed external world
of real absence of things which is
inconceivable it's no really empty you
can't even finish that sentence if
things were truly empty as in don't
exist emptiness is not non-existence
it's only emptiness of certain things a
people are used to who have not seen the
images in their mind and then just just
following the kuntum positive directions
of craving pretty much you say them like
it's a pure image let's finish with us
so the point is emptiness it's an image
in your mind like you can say when I say
emptiness I just have a word emptiness
written in my mind Big E okay so what
are the characteristics of the vignette
you said well it's an empty space okay
empty space is defined as an empty space
by absence of that which is empty of
that is its characteristic that's what
definition of emptiness is doesn't
matter what isn't your so it's a
negative presence or presence of the
absence of certain things
dwell on that image presence of absence
basically it's not a contradiction
because absence is a thing is a thing
that is present so it's the content of
that that's not there but the nature
absence is there what else does a mirror
the same principle in your experience
then
nah yeah sense of ownership
since a master controller because I am
here where what is the content of my
sense of self can you find it can you
find the content of what you are but you
are so with a negative so you're the
absence of content is your presence and
that's why sense of self is assumed in
regard to everything and nothing but
once you study up so the absence so that
the presence of the absence is a real
image I don't need to keep chasing
content and only to verify the image to
find in the content now it's other way
around so by understanding the nature of
emptiness you get to understand the
nature of another and that's why this
room is empty of others and his mind is
established upon the perception of that
image so is this body these five
aggregates are empty of the self as in
the self master controller empty so
there is the sense of self that is the
presence absence of the owner absence of
the owner means non ownership doesn't
mean there was never ever presence of
the absent owner sense of self is absent
owner not seeing it is an absent owner
well you get to then appropriate
everything that you assume that that
cellphones but you lose itself can only
be the absence of the actual owner then
yourself becomes not so automatically so
back onto the image is then
it's important to emphasize your seed
hearing smelling tasting touching would
not be so unless it's already an image
in itself also it's all in my mind then
though it's all in my thought that's an
image then as a reason for so images an
either in your head nor in the things
it's just there in the middle something
is that something is there images of
that manifestation that arise in the
Buddha talks about that's what images
and within that you can discern out the
direction the content of of the sense
objects or or the the absence of sense
object you can creat you can descend the
content like of further images in your
mind as in your own apps tree thinking
and so on and the crucial characteristic
of these images is that you you don't
create them no they don't mean like
based on the previous talk with animal
are' the aspect of resistance in your
thoughts that's what images are that which
that's what images are that which
resists already has some shape already
has some form so to speak you wouldn't
recognize if it wasn't absolutely in
some way there was an image that yeah
exactly it would not be known yeah resistant
it would not be known yeah resistant
yeah exactly you can only can I think a
resistance and then the images is no
resistance is an image the resistance is
already designation accompany and the
designation already resisted out
resistance exactly either way so that an image
exactly either way so that an image
needs to be there so they're all equal
forcing lives to and you could see how I
could perhaps make more sense then you
can see how I can establish your mind
upon the basis of the infinite space 12
and image of infinity the actual
resisting aspect of the thought of
infinity that is body clean it is fully
understand it fully invest effort in it
as the well said fully there a theme of
it as it fully discerned the science of
infinity infinite space and then you get
dwelling your
and abiding in it whether you're walking
sitting eating lying down going to
toilet your mind will be within that
container of infinity meaning that
you're including all meaning that
whatever comes to that will be inferior
to it as well as the boring describe it
being in faded to it the fabric like a
physics passionate about it includes oh
yeah resistance in image that includes
all the other image you used
so people usually swing between the two
look I'm looking or I'm thinking I can't
see anything between so when you talk
about images these are thoughts but now
this is the reality of my senses so
you're gonna be excluding either you
want to see what's in common to both
when I have the experience of an image
when I have the experience of a sight
sound smell taste touch the experiences
is an image error isn't present in
present enduring on its own just like
this like the whole philosophical
tradition is been like swinging swinging
between the empiricists who were selling
the senses come first and then the
rationalist who is saying the movie
thoughts come first senses and thoughts
are only known because there's an image
yeah tip here is an image neither was
ever seeing the practice of casinos
expensive images yeah
as in yeah the grated images can be
reduced it did you kind of encounter in
your average experience that's why
casinos of four elements colors space
and consciousness it's not focusing on a
desk no of course not then the means of
focusing what you're looking at
yes you're not actually seeing it you
can only look at something because it's
already an image because it's already
known as an image so it appeared as an
image so the enduring is an image so
it's more about discerning more that's
why I like like the boy was it sorry
food or who was it
the Mogollon discerning it as different
as as air is basis of air bases of water
based a fire attractive ugly
attractive ugly the same thing yeah cuz
it is yeah it's the block of wood it's
so far down that it if you look at the
more general nature what images it
pertains to it has solidity the image of
solid is there
[Music] the image of heat is there and the image
the image of heat is there and the image
of beauty is there and it is rather
you sir the image of salinity is that
sort of higher ground where you can see
the block of wood yes within the
experience you can see the block of wood
but you see the higher ground is coming
further structurally not the block of
wood you're staring it yeah and that's
why the goodness it like that when you
develop the casinos like his mind gets
like he said my president I don't know
dick casino birth the mind develops upon
the image of Earth image of solid and
that's literally in everything you can
ever perceive has a degree of solid
which means but takes to the into the
element of Earth it's within that his
mind develops upon that he then develops
this passion understanding in the escape
in regards to the image of Earth and
what is then to be said about everything
that's inferior to it you abandon it
completely pour water fire air blue
yellow light and so on the point is the
principle is you get to discern an image
on account of your current thought or
sense objects but you get to understand
there's an image coming first so for
most people they might discern an image
but they always put it second so they'll
put that which is first a second and
their second sight they'll put us first
and that's how natural assumption of
things from the world first come to me
here as in here they're between the two
it's already an image of space in your
mind and that's what's first
structurally you wouldn't have any
concept of distance movement
intentionality if the image is not there
providing you with possibilities of that
so the image yes and when you have a
thought oh now the fundamental that's an
image in your mind there any any
particular image content is has the
nature image sure there is no like image
and now I have something deaf
into an image within an image oh you can
access these images with these images
because I'm with any thought yes you can
have an image oh so I have an image of a
tape measurer of this yellow thing in my
hand and now I can within that start
looking at different components of that
thing and all of those are further
images and even if I don't know what
this is for so I don't have a particular
purpose in my mind of this thing of
color I have shape image of color shape is
I have shape image of color shape is
already in my mind and then oh so then
there is the image in my mind and
there's a thing in my hand thing in my
hand is an image in my mind so it's mine
within the mind within the mind within
the mind within the mind within the mind
the external world within the mind the
internal thoughts in my abstraction
within the mind
so the mind comes first and things can
never leave the mind that mind not the
mind of abstract thinking which is
already within the mind I'm talking
about as in within the image you cannot
possibly relate to it you cannot think
it you cannot designate it you cannot
even fleeting the very aware of what was
that you cannot even ask a question in
regard to it if it's not there at least
to some extent as an image that extent
is an extent of an image that's why the
Cocina literal meaning of casino is
extent yeah totality totality of the
extent in it what the extent of totality
yeah you can't be more specific than
that because that's as specific as it is
can you ask a question about something
so you don't know specifically what it
is but there's something you want to ask
Center that's something that I can't
remember what it was but I question if
there has to be an image there of that
extent that extent of ambiguity the
extent of lack of clarity
oh my mind is empty now it's blank
there is no thoughts in it that's the
thought of the images there
so you truly conceiving an objective
reality free from you is inconceivable
because that's you can only even relate
to it in the wrong manner or right
manner in any manner
cuz it's there as an image enduring how
can you even talk about it or thinking
and so if you're if you are able to
discern the extent of image like like
the innocent of manifestation yeah not
discern everything that has a nature too
many exactly and if you also recognize
the fact that these images have the
characteristic of you know I'm subjected
to them I didn't create them yet they
have a reason the manifest and there is
absolutely no being dispossessed what
they're changing the enduring images oh
I can I can put this I can throw it away
I can use it I can save it I can do lots
of things because an image of it it's
still there for me that image of that
disappearance either through this body
being destroyed or the counterpart it's
necessary whatever of my senses but yes
it is another image exactly you can't
even think of the pure world video
destruction pure I think without having
it manifested as an image in your mind
they're saying it you're subjected to
images so how can you not be subjected
so because if you you know an image is
there for me yeah
so that's so it's afflicting yeah in a
sense of how I'm being subjected to okay
but if I see that image is just there I
want to see that image isn't just a and
but there's an image of for me yeah but
that's an image yeah
it's a secondary to image it's not why
is it secondary it's an image second
they're only in your assumed
relationship between the two images the
content what is the content of for me
the concept of for me what is the
content of that tape what is the content
of it and there's color have a content I
think yeah so I'm saying that when you
say content it's an image not separate
so it's another image that you yet
somehow assumed to be the material
content of my image image I see that's
not an image which means any sense of
materiality or mentality has to be
within an image the type of image type
of image why would you worry about it
it's just instead of two images start
thinking about one she said this is for
me so there is an image of this there's
image for me which is more important
there the image of this sword image for
me well image for me because it's an
accountant for me that I feel and suffer
so you have an image for me which has a
nature of an image so if you understand
the nature of an image for me you
understood the nature of all images that
are for you which is literally anything
you will be perceiving so that's I mean
it's not like comparing and figuring out
the relation between the two images why
because you're failing to understand
this Combinator it which is it's an
image so but if you're thinking about an
image it doesn't pertain for me means
now you're thinking like a second hand
sort of abstractly you want to make it
relevant relevant which means on the
fundamental level of the experience
which is where the appropriation is
where the sense of ownership sense of
artha everything is so that's like
suffering suffering suffering you what
is suffering
you tell Union it's an image whatever
what is suffering when I say suffering
what's present in your mind suffering
what is suffering pain discomfort the
pain and discomfort stands for the image
of suffering it's an image of suffering
image of pain so what is the image of
pain then what are the characteristics
of the image of pain how would you
describe it which is the necessary image
for the image of suffering most image of
pain not immediately
well again I thought I said no one well
whatever you say it's probably gonna be
more accurate than to try to think about
what it is because when I say the image
of pain is like where is the image of
pain the fact that you're thinking about
something means there is the image of
that's there to that extent I'm asking
you tell me the extent of the image of
pain when I ask you what is the image of
pain I'll tell you tell me the right
image of pain what is the extent of the
pain when you hear the decision
uncomfortable not wanted so all these
things have in common no no no no that's
that's in common that's a common
attitude to all these things this
pleasure discomfort you know wanting
means no no no no no no no no no is no
in things or is knowing your attitude in
regard to things in your attitude in
your attitude in regards to things you
subjected to so when is then the
suffering that you said that has a
necessary image the resisting of it so
it's basically then the suffering is not
an image of pain the suffering is in you
saying no to the image of pain but how
can you even say no to an image of pain
to an image without an image because
they are saying no to the image of pain
implies you having well say no to there
is an image implies you have in like you
can move outside of the space of that
has a reason based on on the basis of an
image saying no to this means you can
replace you with something else from the
outside yet all that is within this you
saying no to say responding to an image
by the point with another amazing
so discerning the nature images will
free from suffering then because the
image of pain is not the suffering the
image of discomfort is not the suffering
so when I say I am afflicted by images
that is an image that's an image which
I'm afflicted by yeah that's because of
another image which is not which is your
attitude of this which you haven't been
seen as an image I'm separating them
that's what the necessary reason before
that for the right view is seeing the
sign of your mind and then we didn't now
establish sound of where your mind is
you can start to discern these images -
an image it's the most general image of
where my mind is which most people
engage with the senses in the world and
day to day the love they don't see it
that's why it's a necessary condition
for becoming so the banner sign of the
mind but now this is even further when
we speak about its business
seeing the presence of the enduring
resisting images within that mind of me
or whatever else so not seeing exactly
not seeing your attitude of not seeing
basically the attitude of resisting as
an image you kind of give it
gratuitous we give it more validity on
account of f you shouid separate from
all the images you're resisting - can
you be resisting an image if there is no
image today - again looking but there is
no image of pain can you be resisting it
you can see what yet you somehow assume
that you resisting it is the first and
then just these things come and I'm
moving them away and chasing them away
and accepting them and rejecting them
come it's coming it's good but
phenomenology just recognizing the truth
I'll take them to thee to the extreme
but basically you know just recognizing
that there are these images there these
phenomena there that normally you'll be
there that yeah and that the other can't
not be there and they're so close to you
that you
normally look through the metaphor gran
says yeah and you will be taking for
granted because by looking through them
you you start seeing further through
yeah and that you see further through
and that's how the whole sensuality
proliferate as well because you are also
not indifferent to these things every
image is simultaneously felt pleasantly
are pleasantly neutrally has to be one
of those things has to be and given that
you have attitude in wanting pleasure
avoiding pain means some images would be
wanted which means you'll be going for
the content failing to see the nature of
image and another images will be
rejected means trying to deny the
content failing to see the natural image
and that's how you make bond with image
but if you were to see that which it
wanted that which is not wanted house
images as that but that's sort of common
ground that's women like even these
ambiguous than wanting do the standard
wanting is wanting wanting how would you
describe wanting I've take a particular
example I wanted I want to eat so what
is what is my wanting in this
particularly imply instance okay see
exactly so that's not even it has to be
that thing so you can do both first take
that thing did you have any say in the
manifestation of an image of that thing
if that thing is not sorted because see
I'm not seeing the food now yet I know I
want food how's that possible if the
food is generally entirely solely fully
material how can I even think it it's
not material and mental are images first
and they always remain images now
they're images that are sort of images
of the senses and they're images that
they're images of the mind but they are
all images
and while the senses the five senses
operate there will be the images of the
senses while the mind is their divine
operates they will also be dignity of
the mind
it's not that the images of the census
and then there are also you know the
real objects of those senses
okay object of the sentence an image
upon image of an image of an image or an
image so seeing image means seeing the
mind coming first seeing image Oh an
always seeing image well you don't need
to it's really discerning an image so
like I always have to be seen the image
because you have no choice but to see
anything that is discerning that but
this is certainly what you're seeing so
you to to Jinnah sees images that's all
you can see Aaron sees images at all you
can see the difference is for patrician
army he misconceives images to be there
with them not has being suffered from
his mind yeah
where is well then the whole ideal
separation comes from it assuming
external internal both neither mine not
mine and what we're talking about here
is that that the direction of
unification of mind of Samadhi
unification exactly yeah
that senses that's it because you
discerned the unifying contact the
unifying nature that's when I went when
I asked you first
I said what's in common to you looking
at the tape measure and you're thinking
about not singing what's in common
so it's training in regard to the
ambiguity of images not to clarify it
into detail but to recognize it the
extent of its ambiguity because it's
only ambiguity of the content ambiguity
of the detail not in beginning of the
nature of image and I'm being subjected
to tetramine and not being able to grip
with that kind of recognition of that
ambiguity that's why you don't like
wanting not wanting all these things
become abstract for most people and like
the law reaches I think about emptiness
not self impermanence well imagine how
actually that is an abstract means
you're not seeing that's it you're not
seeing an image of it you're thinking it
which is a we have ii have a thought and
you aren't seeing that for us the an
image as the image that it is exactly
there's an image in your misconceiving
there because there is
mr. buddy see ya so literally anything
any attitude
si wanting yeah so one thing requires
you so let's let's dwell on the you
aspect of wanting me what is the image
of me first image it comes to mind the
most of it is distance me me me me
second about a exactly but that's what
it stands for it yeah you're not
thinking about it then you end up having
all these attitude that it's more than
that but whenever you think that's all
it is shape with the body memory of the
face that you've seen reflection first
point of view yet place me this so while
you have that image of shape of the body
as me which is me to have any say in how
that shape of the body has been
manifested for me subjective I came
before art they can even approach it so
now step outside of it or am I always
secondary to that shape of the body or
that memory of the face of my own face
that stands for when I think me my own
name no that's you you are basically
locked outside of it or sorry locked
inside of you more accurately like if
you look left right up and down whatever
you begin it yeah awesome
can I can i how can I then be the owner
of this when it all I'm doing being
subjected to these images as well that's
all and so there's nothing outside that
oh but there's more there's an image
more even a major from be good if the
beauty of an extent yes more ah but
that's an image yeah dude I'm subjecting
suggesting thing but yes I don't like
the yeah
the I am subjected to images hmm
saying that because it gives me the
impression that I what gives you space
to be a separate line or subjected to
this image but you have to start like
that sure sure sure
okay but about the body the senses yeah
yes the mind and it's subjected to
images that's the nature that's what a
mind is you can't that can't be mind
without images but it okay if I say a
manifestation or subject if that's if
that if that becomes more accurate way
of describing it for you that's fun but
for most people in order to start you
have to stop like that and then
eventually come to click okay but I'm
subjected to this some subjective there
them subjected that I am I am hmm isn't
that another image on subjective and
then you get to upgrade your own
description but as I said the starting
point is the point of ignorance the
point of misconceiving which means you
will not be able to cease immediately
things like the aura Honda's
approximating how are enhances you get
to understand what is really said it
which is what makes you become all dumb
as another because not self is an image
yeah self is an image well you could you
could you could say that yeah so one
sense of self it's as you say as we kind
of just described it's kind of a becomes
a more fundamental image and everything
else that comes to your senses like
whether it seeing a little taste in
touching you have you said it's up it's
for me so it's that image is in common
to all these senses so what if I were to
then understand in a band on that image
abandon in a sense with this experience
this passion and remove the ownership of
it you have remove the ownership of the
five senses you have removed sensuality
sense desire by by removing the
ownership of this image of self yeah
exactly then all these things come through
then all these things come through
that's a good man by establishing mind
upon the totality of the extent
solidity totality of the extent of a
dinosaur what I want to translate it
basically by practicing casinos you
establish a mind to sell ever everything
inferior to that is abandoned or you
know perceptions of the forest abandon
perceptions of the village they didn't
feel your perceptions in regard to it as
in either way which doesn't matter how
particular perceptions get this is what
I have in common and you abandoned that
common ground so whether its sight sound
smell taste touch the common ground is
image of me for me mine
I am your band on that depend on all
these inferior images within that image
and by abandoning means not preventing
it from arising because you haven't
created it's arising to begin with it
was never a problem a bad thing it means
removing the gratuitous as attitudes of
resisting it or craving for it and you
will crave for things for as long as you
think you can create your things fully
understanding that craving is impossible
the way you assumed it that's how you
stop assuming how can we cry for
something let's all do that as I said oh
I don't see the food now but I want to
eat I crave the food when I say I crave
the food if my craving is in the food if
the food is the craving I would need to
be in contact with it you know it's to
crave for it hey you yep I don't even
have food then you are in comes that fit
exactly but not the content of the
domain did not go with the image exactly
Syrian is also my craving is then on the
level of the image yet I don't stay on
the level of the image when I crave I go
out and seek food yes and steal food and
attack and kill them work and learn
whatever rightly or wrongly I go out and seek
rightly or wrongly I go out and seek
these objects because I crave vinegar to
the image of food and they get spared
then with a discomfort of hunger so
they're naturally associating them
seeking this food that I can put in my
belly Olivier's helps my gratuitous attitude
Olivier's helps my gratuitous attitude
of resisting pain
for physical nature discomfort of hunger
but discount for the fungi again it's an
image an image that literally could put
anything in my eat it you wouldn't worry
about it taste then because you fully
state with the discomfort of the hunger
is the context okay I have to deal with
this discomfort because the body will
die I do need to crave for it in order
to do it but most people don't act on
that level most people either on another
whole layer added to it which is yeah
I'm hungry but I want particular taste
and that's another image that can never
be anything other than an image but you
assume taste to be in the objects of
your senses which is another image but
you assume the materiality of it
independent of it and that's what
sensuality is wrong because it's a
perversion of off of the right order of
things if you weren't perverting the
order it wouldn't be unwholesome it
wouldn't be wrong so things that don't
favor the order or not love such as
hunger putting something in your stomach
so you're not hungry you don't you don't
you don't miss can see what comes first
and the purpose then cannot become
corrupted that's the whole instruction
of the world to mindfully eat mindfully
as you not observe every movement of
your tongue but mindful of the purpose
while you're eating like I will eat for
this reason for this reason for I will
not eat for this reason for death the
mindfulness of eating not chewing
chewing slowly yes now why am i eating
is caused hunger is there that so you
serve an imager for hunger it's kind of
image of hunger disappears as in none
gets replaced image of a non hunger you
stop eating not even a second but if
this tastes because of all that became
far removed now there was never the
purpose of the taste to begin with the
only reason you were even attracted to
tastes is because of the pressure of the
hunger yet you completely then as a result of
yet you completely then as a result of
it
your children assumed taste to being the
matter of things that you can somehow
access through your eating X is the
external world
that's another image in your mind but
you think that's not that's not an image
that's the world that's the reality and
by doing so you always remain bound to
then that extent of assumption that's
the sensuality the central thirst
wanting the object how can you want the
object unless there is an image of that
you're wanting in your mind and then
what is the object even if I'm consuming
and crushing eating devouring enjoying
whatever object in a schedule you're
fully within that and when you fully
understand that you cannot even conceive
outside of it you stop conceiving
outside of it which is central domain
which is the assumption of sensuality
contemplating images be quantum lineages
nothing in an abstract sense but in a
sense that they're already there
discerning the images contemplating
images means discerning it is whatever
it is my experiences are called my body
image of the body present here I don't
need to look at it the fact that I can
say my body is here even if I close my
eyes means I haven't even draw it the
factor then I can know what to look at
when I say my body is here means I have
an image is there how would you even
know where to look for it unless the
majority implies the direction of the
space respects to this position and so
on yeah I mean I mean I thought my eyes
open still image it like he's just fun
about challenges there is an image of
the senses and the image of the mind but
image is there
and you can have both the images there
while the image of the senses and limit
of the mind is there but you can't
attend to it to the same extent as to be
one that's where the six senses so the
image is there in the six types of
images are there on account of the six
senses being there it's the sense sense
basis Sally Athena I have to know it's like a
Sally Athena I have to know it's like a
like a Fiat that the extent that's all
in an image within which then decides
come which are further images within
that extent if there is no field where
sites are sites will not be manifested
at all
so understanding the sixth sense basis
means you're become sensuality not by
dealing managing getting rid of the
objects of your sad spaces uprooting the
framework of the basis uprooting in the
removing ownership misconceiving lack of
discernment not seeing it as and there
is an image to present in yours that's
right like suitors they deal with this
they talk about this often like for
people and delicious abstract sounds
abstract sounds and then the idea of
abstraction from a mind they cannot
understand the nature of abstraction
then the other pursuing the extension of
this already culture is the cistern on
material reality and then you think all
these meditation experiences get to
pertain to the extension of this will su
external reality came from it space it's
infinity space
neither perception nor perception
becomes immediately latest
transcendental universe elsewhere mangy
Santa's magical area where is it fun
that images that obviously are present
but need to be discerned you know the 10
yes or the transcend yeah that's all I'm
sorry crystal isn't that in majima one
by one
he's developing all the jhanas and then
all the basis of infinite space and so
on he would ask himself Oh is the mote
in this as an Easter higher is there
greater than this but he wouldn't go
around to find it he was just looking
the same thing and then see that there
is more to it he would look at the same
log yes good we read a book what's the
night let me find another piece of log
that's more a more liquid than than than
the solid yeah no it's within the same
there is more so it's more on the level
of the images now the Lord on the level
of fantasizing about theory of linear
connections between things that you
already assumed to be in fact isn't each
each progression progressive stage more
like the sort of negative of what it is
here but that negative is also Pratt is
also a part that's why there is even in
conclusion experience there is the
element of Nirvana present which is why
some people some traditions completely
then jump to conclusion sing us so we
are already in Ivana because the Buddha
said we all have element of Nibbana we
do element means present absence so it's
it's present as an absence means it's
possible to discern it you know creates
bring the context of it develop the
theme of it as the Buddha would say and
that's how you develop it but saying
that presence absence means arm already
in that which is absent because it's
present as an absence well that's
jumping the gun so there is the element
of Nirvana in everyone's experience yet
the actual abana
there is the presence of it in
everyone's XP
and that's another good thing to reflect
because you stop assuming it to be at
the end of the world or the end of your
meditation observational technique no
it's already here every minute of your
life and Vanunu bond is with you
understand the theme of that element
understanding that understand the the
characteristics of that absence that is
nirvana for you and in absence of greed
absence of aversion absurd illusion
finished shares the qualities of all
we've been talking about this color yeah
so easily beyond when 30-pot asks how is
the modernist means exactly that
discerning it as a present absence
discerning it as a possibility to
develop and develop and then later on as
a city says he will develop it oh yeah
he verified that there is more there was
more now that present absent he's not absent
now that present absent he's not absent
any more because he fully discerned the
context of that which was absent if
there was not even present even a tiny
bit as an absence you couldn't go in
that direction
how can you discern something that
doesn't exist hence the element of
Nirvana you know the older doctors the
Buddha lists it's not the physical
element scattered in the world that you
collect like gems of something no it's
the basically the present absences the
absences of all the absence of this
passion they have to all these themes
are present absences or possibilities to
develop in the practice of elements as
in the present as absences but again it
has to be an image to that extent even
if you complete after a sensual putana
Nibbana Nibbana
what is Nibbana you have some image even
if it's an image of a world and that's
what I mean
if closer than represents that ambiguous
image close to represents what Nibbana
is in your experience then when you get
to like theorize what nirvana is because
at least you're looking in the direction
of that absence that is present as such
that's why some monks needs very little
detailed instruction some acts needed
more
with a minimum instruction they would've
turn to the right direction of the right
absence and then dwell on it and and
understand the context of it and by
doing so develop even John is the same
principle the world we said developed
the theme of John like jhanas are
basically so close to the point of view
that's where people that's what takes
effort to attain to tend to develop it
it's not like John is figuring something
out at the end of a certain effort the
John is basically the way you are seeing
regarding things did you think of
polluted with your own ignorance we do
not lost the version and habits so its
removal this pollution to basically
recognize that certain imperturbable
basis unified basis well why do I think
about the sense object rather think
about joy grief an image has to be there
enduring and you become discerning of
the enduring image regardless of the
content of whatever points you that's
already a unified mind and that's
already John on account of any
experience you can have
that's all those different different
ways of entering jhana with commentaries
compiled from the suitors but like
looking at the cops yeah established
John and my emphasis the Bacchus W Janet
I like this result in Jonah John is an
attitude of unification upon certain dis
sermons the sermon of this passion this
sermon of yeah I got like sensuality
abandoning in that side so it's not
suitable the content it's exactly the
context of yeah exactly the
characteristics of the unified mind
so that's always doesn't matter the
experience whether oh I'm feeling good
I'm feeling bad on physical discomfort
physical comfort whatever it is does
matter how complex it is how ambiguous
it is how contents kind of inclined it
is image is there has to be there any
idea of direction any idea of the
movement - for against both neither
requires an image to be the rendering
some ambiguous image so it's recognizing
learning how to discern an image in its
ambiguity not trying to replace it with
content that you deemed a wordy
threshold because how can you be
exercising the threshold of necessary
content unless there is an image that
needs to be built up to that level I
just think it's about being skill like I
said being skills and images which is
being skilled and dumber he's killing
the mind seeing the mind quickly you
know like as soon as it arise as soon as
the damage is manifest he sees it
exactly for what it is he doesn't need
to Oh catch himself down the line and
then what you will need them in the
beginning that's just like the word
frame which is Dhamma sure domina and
that's why this teaching is the teaching
the Dhamma the image the Buddha was
teaching the image the fundamental image
the universal image in common to any
five aggregates anywhere in the any
union Universal realm come to see the
image otherwise from an understanding
and that images understanding the nature
images extensive images external images
image extent not image extent in terms
of telling you how many there are
extent of the nature so they were little
like if he was talking about all these
images is because it was the context of
understanding the nature and what is the
nature of images cannot beyond cannot be
appropriated cannot be owes you cannot
controlled she was subjected to to them
not other way around you understand that
you are free from the entire samsara
Orlin absolutely nothing left samsara
universe rebirth
yeah all these different directions what
do you have in common they had an image
this image there is a specific like you
know maybe ambiguous but is such an
images there yeah what else is there
when I have these images oh it's always
me he's sensible another image of me is
always there yeah so that's kind of more
in common to all these other things that
you've been dwelling on so like why
don't you dwell on something that's more
in common to those particular things as
opposed to chasing down particular leads
and that's how in every table you will
end up to like self awareness
responsibility on to you all these
things we talked about
standards together have refined images
they would have I defined images so even
if you're refining your images means
you're not seeing them as images you're
basically tracing the content which is
another image that you fail to see hence
the idea of refinement or replacing it
with another image I'm very blunt
ambiguous because any images the true
refinement of an ambiguous image is to
recognize its ambiguity to be an image
that's how you find it you don't refine
it by by providing content for it
that psychologize asian basically just
now we're talking this whole idea
concept of time you say concept let you
think that's meaningless well my lunch
establish your mind upon the unified
image and meaningless being distracted
becomes inconceivable meaningless as in
it ceases it's not there any
your mood is an image yeah
has has a shape has has a color to it so
now it's easy to name some time has
weight to it that's why they were to
describe the decided on of the Fujita or
elated expensive shrunk depressed elated
big small mind because yet those are
images that might is that is what man is
not I'm thinking elation no it's like
you're discerning on the current mood an
image that's implicit in it but you had
nothing to do it you have created it you
could not have created an image
impossible I'm creating an image is an
image that you are subjected to now
you're trying to provide a secondary
content to it they would feel more like
yours so you've become with an image of
the possibility of creating images